<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blogs | Developing Jon]]></title>
  <link href="http://jonr22.github.io/blog/categories/blogs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jonr22.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-12T15:52:54-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jonr22.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jon Reimels]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jonr2219@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://jonr22.github.io/blog/2014/03/12/octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T15:24:39-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jonr22.github.io/blog/2014/03/12/octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve just started using the <a href="http://octopress.org/">octopress</a> blogging framework (A blogging
framework for hackers) and so far I really like it. It&rsquo;s super easy to setup, assuming you&rsquo;re
a developer / hacker (and especially if you&rsquo;re familiar with ruby). If you&rsquo;re interested, the
documentation on their website is very easy to follow.</p>

<p>Previously I was using wordpress, and while it&rsquo;s a fine platform, I never wanted to pay for
it, so my ability to customize felt very limited. Now with octopress I have complete
flexibility and since it&rsquo;s open source I have access to the code. In fact I&rsquo;ve already looked
around the code a bit to help me find the sass variables I needed to customize the look and feel
of the site.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Octopress has been setup so that it&rsquo;s very easy to customize, especially for small CSS changes.
They&rsquo;ve nicely setup a <code>custom</code> directory with sass stylesheets that get loaded last, so that
you can override any CSS settings and SASS variables. Overall it seems very well thought out.</p>

<p>Combine this with the ability to host the site on github for free and you&rsquo;ve got a great setup.
Not to mention, if you do much with github, then you&rsquo;re probably somewhat familiar with the
markdown language, so you already have the knowledge needed to create posts.</p>

<p>Another benefit that I like is being able to write my posts in my favorite editor, vim!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
